<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity>
  <Identity>
    <History>
        Han Xin grew up in bitter poverty. He was so poor, in fact, that he constantly struggled to get enough food to survive, often having to rely on others. For that, he was despised by his town's residents. Very early in his life, he even lost his mother and didn't have the financial means to properly bury her. So, when rebellions broke out throughout the empire, Han Xin saw his chance and joined the rebel leader, Xiang Yu.
        Xiang Yu was a warlord renown for his bravery and considered the greatest warrior of his time. Together with his elite soldiers, he was regarded as almost invincible, even having defeated armies twenty times the size of his own.
        It's said that Han Xin often made tactical suggestions to higher officers, but his advice was not taken seriously and was often ignored. So, after Xiang Yu had defeated the Qin dynasty and split China into eighteen kingdoms, Han Xin decided to move over to the kingdom of Han under Liu Bang. Maybe because Liu Bang came, unlike other warlords, from destitute backgrounds as well. However, it didn't work out for him there either: for a small crime, he was put in jail and barely escaped execution. Only when he was about to desert again and find his luck somewhere else did some of Liu Bang's advisors, who appeared to be very impressed by the young soldier, gave him a chance and led him to Liu Bang himself. Han Xin was then, surprisingly, appointed chief commander of Liu Bang's armies.
        And Han Xin didn't have to wait long to prove himself. As conflicts arose between several kingdoms, he took the chance. Han Xin sent soldiers to rebuild the Gallery Roads, the passage to other kingdoms, as a distraction. He simultaneously led an army to attack the neighboring kingdom. This plan worked. And Liu Bang's advisors weren't mistaken: Han Xin managed to defeat kingdom after kingdom, even though his troops were often outnumbered and very inexperienced. And victories were often due to his well-thought-out plans. A good example is the Battle of Jingxing in 205 BC, where he made clever use of the terrain and applied psychological tricks to decisively win with a small militia army outnumbered seven to one.
        After having conquered the entirety of Western and Northern China, even Xiang Yu, for whom Han Xin had fought some years before, was impressed and, at the same time, alarmed by Han Xin's success. He offered Han Xin to let him have  Northern China if, in return, he joined him in his fight against Liu Bang. Han Xin, however, declined and stayed with Liu Bang.
        He marched southwards to assist Liu Bang, who had fought unsuccessfully against Xiang Yu. Quite the opposite, actually; despite his greater forces, Liu Bang had suffered heavy defeats against Xiang Yu and his war veterans. Han Xin, though, didn't make the mistake of believing he was in an advantageous position because of his army's greater numbers. He instead carried out small ambushes on Xiang Yu's army, which was exhausted from the long conflict. And at the Battle of Gaixia in 202 BC, he led Xiang Yu into a canyon and, in combination with more psychological tricks, eventually defeated the thought-to-be invincible Xiang Yu. Following this victory, Liu Bang founded the Han dynasty, and Han Xin was celebrated as a hero.
        Unfortunately, his story doesn't have a good ending, as only a few years later, Liu Bang started to fear Han Xin's brilliance and influence, accused him of rebellion, and assassinated him.
        But Han Xin's legacy stayed. While Xiang Yu might have known how to win battles, Han Xin knew how to win wars, proving the importance of strategy over pure fighting skill. In his entire career as a general, Han Xin never lost a battle, helped found the longest-lasting dynasty in Chinese history, and entered history books as the single greatest general of his era.  
    </History>
  </Identity>
</Entity>
