<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity>
  <Identity>
    <History>
      Liu Bang was born and raised as a peasant during the waning years of the Qin dynasty. He was known for being a rebellious yet charismatic child, often getting into trouble with the law. Despite his rebellious nature, he made friends with several officials in the government. They, in turn, appointed him to be the local sheriff.
      One day, Liu Bang was ordered to escort a group of prisoners to help build the First Emporer's mausoleum. On the way, a prisoner escaped. If Liu Bang arrived a man short, he would be executed. And if he arrived late, having spent time recapturing the man, he would also be killed. So instead, Liu Bang let all the prisoners free and started a revolt.
      Over the next few years of fight, Liu Bang became a successful general. However, it was Xiang Yu, the rebel leader, who ultimately defeated the Qin dynasty. Xiang Yu split China's land into eighteen kingdoms and appointed nobles, or his generals, as rulers. Liu Bang received the land of Han.
      However, this arrangement proved unstable. War broke out between the kingdoms, and Liu Bang conquered several others of his rivals. Despite numerical superiority, however, Liu Bang suffered heavy defeats against Xiang Yu.
      It wasn't until Liu Bang allied with other states that he managed to defeat Xiang Yu in the Battle of Gaixia. Xiang Yu took his own life, and Liu Bang had united China, founding the Han dynasty in 202 BC. Liu Bang appointed himself the first emperor, the Emperor Gaozu of Han.
      Liu Bang kept many elements from the Qin dynasty. However, he did not forget his upbringing in the peasantry. He implemented policies lowering taxes on peasants, which strengthened rural agriculture and restored the war-impaired economy. He also reduced the severity of punishments from the Qin dynasty. This made Liu Bang very popular, especially among commoners. Inspired by a Confucianist teacher and philosopher, Liu Bang introduced Confucianism as the state ideology, in contrast to the legalistic approach present in the Qin dynasty.
      Although Liu Bang died of illness in 195 BC, the dynasty he had founded would go on to (with a short interruption) become the longest-lasting and one of the most prosperous in Chinese history. 
    </History>
  </Identity>
</Entity>
