<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity>
  <Identity>
    <History>
        The Argyraspides (translating to “silver shields”) were an elite Macedonian unit that was adopted by later Hellenistic armies. It is believed that they originally were hypaspists who, during Alexander's Indian campaign, upgraded and decorated their gear with silver and gold. They were a prestigious, special force known to be the fiercest and most skilled contingent of the army.
        Soon after Alexander's campaign had come to an end, the Argyraspides unit was dissolved. After all, the men had, at this point, been continuously fighting for over 20 years; most were over the age of 50! However, when Alexander died shortly after and war between the proclaimed successors (Diadochi) broke out, they were called back to arms.
        During the first war of Diadochi, the Argyraspides fought for Perdiccas, but eventually, faltered from a lack of military success, turned against him and revolted. It was their own commander, Antigenes, who ultimately murdered Perdiccas.
        During the second war of Diadochi, the Argyraspides joined Eumenes, and in spite of their old age—many over 70 at this point—they proved extremely valuable in a series of battles. At the Battle of Gabiene against Antigonus' forces, they pushed the enemy line back and even managed to retreat in an organized manner from the lost battlefield despite being encircled. Their families and all loot acquired over several decades, however, were captured in the meantime. This pushed many individual soldiers to want to switch sides. And despite Antigenes, their commander, staying loyal this time, the Argyraspides ultimately caught and handed over their own supreme general, Eumenes—again—and deserted as a whole.
        Antigonus, with a passionate dislike against this unit, to render them harmless, consequently ordered to disperse the soldiers over the entire empire, allegedly with the intention to have them killed in some way.
    </History>
  </Identity>
</Entity>
