<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity>
  <Identity>
    <History>
        Although many ancient civilizations constructed crossbows, the Chinese were the ones who used them extensively. In the Han dynasty, crossbows were mass-produced and a widely-used weapon, especially among militias. The use of crossbows proved to be an important advantage in battle for the Han, most notably in the wars against the Xiognu, a nomadic horse people. The crossbow was a truly revolutionary weapon for several reasons.
        First, crossbows were very easy to use. It took years, if not an entire lifetime, to master the bow. On the other hand, even people who had never held a crossbow before could, in as little as a few days, learn to use it. Aiming, for example, was very easy; Han crossbows even had a scale built in, indicating how high to aim to hit the target at a specific distance. The low effort needed to train a good crossbowman was especially advantageous because the Han's armies largely consisted of militia. When war broke out and the Han dynasty could easily raise an army of thousands of peasants equipped with crossbows, each was as dangerous as any archer after years-long training.
        Second, crossbows were drawn differently than bows. It was placed on the ground, and the bowman squatted down, grabbed the bowstring with his hands, and pulled it upwards. Because this movement utilizes arm, back, and leg muscles, more force gets exerted than through the motion of drawing a bow. This meant the crossbow could be tensed higher and fire arrows at a higher speed compared to bows. In fact, according to experiments, a Han crossbow required almost double the pulling force of a typical bow used by the Xiognu. But it also launched the arrow at 20 percent higher speed, up to 50 percent greater distance, and with a higher penetrating power. An arrow hitting its target caused dangerous, if not lethal, damage, even through the Xiognu's typical leather armor. In this regard, the Han crossbow was far superior to the Xiognu's bows.
        However, the crossbow had a major drawback, and that was its reloading time. A bow could shoot arrows many times faster than any crossbow. Crossbows were too slow to actually stop cavalry charges. To compensate, Han crossbowmen shot alternately to maintain a continuous hail of arrows. And, because of the way the crossbows were cocked, those with this high level of required pull force were exclusive to infantry.
    </History>
  </Identity>
</Entity>
