<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="template_unit_fauna_hunt_defensive">
  <Attack>
    <Melee>
      <AttackName>Tusks</AttackName>
      <Damage>
        <Hack>12</Hack>
        <Pierce>12</Pierce>
      </Damage>
      <MaxRange>4</MaxRange>
      <PrepareTime>500</PrepareTime>
      <RepeatTime>1000</RepeatTime>
      <RestrictedClasses datatype="tokens">Structure Ship Siege</RestrictedClasses>
    </Melee>
  </Attack>
  <Footprint>
    <Square width="3.0" depth="6.0"/>
    <Height>3.5</Height>
  </Footprint>
  <Health>
    <Max>200</Max>
  </Health>
  <Identity>
    <GenericName>Hippopotamus</GenericName>
    <SpecificName>Hippopotamus amphibius</SpecificName>
    <Icon>gaia/fauna_hippopotamus.png</Icon>
    <History>
        “The river-horse is sacred in the district of Papremis, but for the other Egyptians he is not sacred; and this is the appearance which he presents: he is four-footed, cloven-hoofed like an ox, flat-nosed, with a mane like a horse and showing teeth like tusks, with a tail and voice like a horse, and in size as large as the largest ox; and his hide is so exceedingly thick that when it has been dried shafts of javelins are made of it.” -- Herodotus Histories Book 2 Paragraph 71
        The animal which Herodotus just describes is the hippopotamus. And while what Herodotus describes does not sound like the Hippopotamus amphibious, we know it is true because hippopotamus means river horse.
       The hippopotamus is the largest living land animal, barring the elephant. They can weigh more than 8,000 pounds (3,628.74 kilograms) and be 5 feet (1.52 meters) tall at the shoulder. Of course, being the second-biggest land animal, the Hippo spends a lot of time in the water. Its eyes and nostrils are situated high on its head, so the rest of it can spend the day dozing in the water, at least until night, when they climb onto land to graze.
    </History>
  </Identity>
  <Loot>
    <xp>40</xp>
  </Loot>
  <ResourceSupply>
    <Max>400</Max>
  </ResourceSupply>
  <Sound>
    <SoundGroups>
      <select>actor/fauna/animal/lion_select.xml</select>
      <attack_melee>actor/fauna/animal/lion_attack.xml</attack_melee>
      <death>actor/fauna/animal/lion_death.xml</death>
    </SoundGroups>
  </Sound>
  <StatusBars>
    <HeightOffset>4.5</HeightOffset>
  </StatusBars>
  <VisualActor>
    <Actor>fauna/hippopotamus.xml</Actor>
  </VisualActor>
</Entity>
