<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="template_structure_military">
  <Cost>
    <BuildTime>120</BuildTime>
    <Resources>
      <wood>200</wood>
    </Resources>
  </Cost>
  <Footprint>
    <Square width="22.0" depth="22.0"/>
    <Height>12.0</Height>
  </Footprint>
  <GarrisonHolder>
    <Max>1</Max>
    <List datatype="tokens">Infantry Healer</List>
  </GarrisonHolder>
  <Health>
    <Max>2000</Max>
    <SpawnEntityOnDeath>decay|rubble/rubble_stone_4x4</SpawnEntityOnDeath>
  </Health>
  <Identity>
    <GenericName>Forge</GenericName>
    <SelectionGroupName>template_structure_military_forge</SelectionGroupName>
    <Tooltip>Research attack damage and damage resistance technologies.</Tooltip>
    <Classes datatype="tokens">-ConquestCritical</Classes>
    <VisibleClasses datatype="tokens">Town Forge</VisibleClasses>
    <Icon>structures/blacksmith.png</Icon>
    <Requirements>
      <Techs datatype="tokens">phase_town</Techs>
    </Requirements>
    <History>
        Blacksmithing, the ability to smelt and shape metal, was vital for ancient civilizations. Blacksmiths generally enjoyed an elevated status and the reputation of being very skilled individuals; their valuable contribution to society was highly esteemed. Knowledge and skill in metallurgy were significant and essential for technological and societal advancement of any civilization.
         Metalworking influenced many aspects of life and history, such as warfare, agriculture, commerce, art, and culture. By forging sharp and durable weaponry, blacksmiths enhanced the capabilities of military forces. By crafting tools such as axes, hoes, plows, and scythes, they improved farming and resource gathering efficiency. They made household items such as pots and vases, which increased living standards in their community. Blacksmiths falicated construction and architecture by  producing nails, hinges, locks, chains, clamps, hooks, and other metal goods, and by shaping horseshoes, farriers helped optimize transportation and mobility. The high demand and supply for such useful goods led to commercial expansion and economic growth. But the significance of a blacksmith's work extends far beyond functionality. Metalworks were a way of artistic expression and a reflection of cultural beliefs and values. As should be clear by now, antique civilization in its entirety relied on these skilled individuals mastering the methods of shaping metal to function. The knowledge and experience in blacksmithing very accurately show a civilization's societal and technological progress.
    </History>
  </Identity>
  <Loot>
    <wood>40</wood>
  </Loot>
  <Obstruction>
    <Static width="17.0" depth="17.0"/>
  </Obstruction>
  <ProductionQueue/>
  <Researcher>
    <Technologies datatype="tokens">
      soldier_attack_melee_01
      soldier_attack_melee_02
      soldier_attack_melee_03
      soldier_attack_melee_03_variant
      soldier_attack_ranged_01
      soldier_attack_ranged_02
      soldier_attack_ranged_03
      soldier_resistance_hack_01
      soldier_resistance_hack_02
      soldier_resistance_hack_03
      soldier_resistance_pierce_01
      soldier_resistance_pierce_02
      soldier_resistance_pierce_03
      archer_attack_spread
    </Technologies>
  </Researcher>
  <Sound>
    <SoundGroups>
      <select>interface/select/building/sel_forge.xml</select>
      <constructed>interface/complete/building/complete_forge.xml</constructed>
    </SoundGroups>
  </Sound>
  <TerritoryInfluence>
    <Radius>38</Radius>
    <Weight>30000</Weight>
  </TerritoryInfluence>
  <Vision>
    <Range>32</Range>
  </Vision>
  <VisualActor>
    <FoundationActor>structures/fndn_5x5.xml</FoundationActor>
  </VisualActor>
</Entity>
