<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="template_structure_military">
  <Auras datatype="tokens">
    structures/arsenal_repair
  </Auras>
  <Cost>
    <BuildTime>180</BuildTime>
    <Resources>
      <wood>300</wood>
    </Resources>
  </Cost>
  <Footprint>
    <Square width="30.0" depth="30.0"/>
    <Height>12.0</Height>
  </Footprint>
  <GarrisonHolder>
    <Max>5</Max>
    <List datatype="tokens">Siege</List>
  </GarrisonHolder>
  <Health>
    <Max>2000</Max>
    <SpawnEntityOnDeath>decay|rubble/rubble_stone_6x6</SpawnEntityOnDeath>
  </Health>
  <Identity>
    <GenericName>Arsenal</GenericName>
    <SelectionGroupName>template_structure_military_arsenal</SelectionGroupName>
    <Tooltip>Train Champion Infantry Crossbowmen, construct Siege Engines, and research Siege Engine technologies.</Tooltip>
    <VisibleClasses datatype="tokens">City Arsenal</VisibleClasses>
    <Icon>structures/siege_workshop.png</Icon>
    <Requirements>
      <Techs datatype="tokens">phase_city</Techs>
    </Requirements>
    <History>
        For a long time, when besieging a city, attackers just tried to force the population of the besieged city to capitulate by cutting supply lines. However, this could take a very long time, with some sieges lasting months or even years. This brought many challenges for both defenders and attackers. They had to deal with supply shortages, logistic problems, sinking morale, and sometimes diseases. It is unknown exactly when, but somewhere in the first half of the first millennial BC, attackers started building and using various siege engines, such as battering rams, to breach walls and other fortifications, allowing them to directly attack and plunder the city. In the centuries to come, siege engines, ranging from simple battering rams and stone-hurling machines to giant siege towers, often played a crucial role in warfare.
        High-quality siege engines were really sought after by some military leaders. Often times, they would have professional engineers working for them, actively developing new weapons. However, production and transportation of siege engines were very challenging. They required large amounts of wood, metal, leather, and rope, as well as specialized tools and workers. Some siege engines could be moved on wheels; others had to, whenever needed, be dismantled, carried to the site of siege, and then reassembled on location. Especially during long sieges, the attackers would also build siege engines right on the spot using local materials.
    </History>
  </Identity>
  <Loot>
    <wood>60</wood>
  </Loot>
  <Obstruction>
    <Static width="29.0" depth="29.0"/>
  </Obstruction>
  <ProductionQueue/>
  <Researcher>
    <Technologies datatype="tokens">
      siege_attack
      siege_cost_time
      siege_health
      siege_pack_unpack
      siege_bolt_accuracy
    </Technologies>
  </Researcher>
  <Sound>
    <SoundGroups>
      <constructed>interface/complete/building/complete_barracks.xml</constructed>
      <select>interface/select/building/sel_barracks.xml</select>
    </SoundGroups>
  </Sound>
  <TerritoryInfluence>
    <Radius>38</Radius>
  </TerritoryInfluence>
  <Trainer>
    <BatchTimeModifier>0.7</BatchTimeModifier>
    <Entities datatype="tokens">
      units/{civ}/champion_infantry_crossbowman
      units/{civ}/siege_scorpio_packed
      units/{civ}/siege_polybolos_packed
      units/{civ}/siege_oxybeles_packed
      units/{civ}/siege_lithobolos_packed
      units/{civ}/siege_ballista_packed
      units/{civ}/siege_ram
      units/{civ}/siege_tower
    </Entities>
  </Trainer>
  <Vision>
    <Range>40</Range>
  </Vision>
  <VisualActor>
    <FoundationActor>structures/fndn_8x8.xml</FoundationActor>
  </VisualActor>
</Entity>
