<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="template_structure_special">
  <Auras datatype="tokens">
    structures/theater
  </Auras>
  <BuildRestrictions>
    <Category>Theater</Category>
  </BuildRestrictions>
  <Cost>
    <BuildTime>500</BuildTime>
    <Resources>
      <wood>200</wood>
      <stone>600</stone>
      <metal>200</metal>
    </Resources>
  </Cost>
  <Footprint replace="">
    <Circle radius="25"/>
    <Height>10.0</Height>
  </Footprint>
  <Health>
    <Max>3000</Max>
  </Health>
  <Identity>
    <GenericName>Theater</GenericName>
    <SelectionGroupName>template_structure_special_theater</SelectionGroupName>
    <VisibleClasses datatype="tokens">Theater</VisibleClasses>
    <Icon>structures/theater.png</Icon>
    <History>
        In Ancient Greece theaters were magnificent constructions, built so that the voices of the performers would reach to every seat. The Theaters consisted of the stage, a place for the musicians and the seats (the theatron)
        There were three genres performed the Tragedy, Comedy, and Saytr Play. Tragedy plays are often thought to be an extension of ancient rites that were performed for Dionysus. Tragedies were solemn-- well ,tragedies  detailing conflicts between men and the gods. Which, often as not ended ill for the protagonists.
        The Genre of Comedy, evolved over the years, first there was Old Comedy (archaia) Old Comedy was crude attacks at political figures. Next was Middle comedy where the attacks focused less on individual people and more at society in general. Finally, New came during the reign of the Macedoines  there was  New Comedy which focused more on everyday life.
        The last Genre the Saytr play is a mixture of both and is called Saytr because it has a chorus of Saytrs who make crude jokes to lighten the mood.
        Greek plays are far different from even Shakspeare’s play. At it’s heyday there were at the highest only three actors who with aid of often grotesque masks played all the parts. They were acompanied a chorus of twelve singers.
        During the reign of Alexander the Great, Greek Theater spread across the land and was later even enjoyed in ancient Rome.
    </History>
  </Identity>
  <Loot>
    <wood>40</wood>
    <stone>120</stone>
    <metal>40</metal>
  </Loot>
  <Obstruction>
    <Static width="40" depth="46"/>
  </Obstruction>
  <Sound>
    <SoundGroups>
      <select>interface/select/building/sel_greek_theater.xml</select>
      <constructed>interface/complete/building/complete_greek_theater.xml</constructed>
    </SoundGroups>
  </Sound>
  <TerritoryInfluence>
    <Root>false</Root>
    <Radius>100</Radius>
    <Weight>40000</Weight>
  </TerritoryInfluence>
  <Vision>
    <Range>40</Range>
  </Vision>
</Entity>
