<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="template_structure_military_barracks">
  <Footprint>
    <Square width="25.0" depth="25.0"/>
    <Height>12.0</Height>
  </Footprint>
  <Health>
    <SpawnEntityOnDeath>decay|rubble/rubble_stone_5x5</SpawnEntityOnDeath>
  </Health>
  <Identity>
    <Civ>athen</Civ>
    <SpecificName>Stratopedon</SpecificName>
    <History>
       The Classical Athenian education and training system was meant to teach both physical and intellectual skills and to prepare students for times of peace and war. It was, however, exclusive to the sons of free Athenian citizens. Girls were tutored at home by either their mothers or private teachers.
        There was no public education in Athens. Boys went to private schools, which were relatively inexpensive, so most boys could attend for at least a couple of years. There, they learned how to write and read, as well as mathematics, music, rhetoric, literature (reading famous and important works such as The Iliad and Odyssey), and politics. Physical training contained activities such as running, jumping, wrestling, and boxing at the gymnasium. For many boys, elementary education ended around the age of 15, and only those who could afford it stayed in school for a few more years.
        Between the ages of 18 and 20, the young men underwent two years of mandatory military training called “ephebeia”. It included practicing hoplite combat, learning how to fight with a spear and shield as well as ranged weapons like bows, slings, and javelins. At a later stage in the “ephebeia”, the men were sent as patrolmen to guard forts around the city-state. At the age of 20, they were released but remained liable for military service until they were 60.
    </History>
  </Identity>
  <Obstruction>
    <Static width="20.0" depth="20.0"/>
  </Obstruction>
  <VisualActor>
    <Actor>structures/athenians/barracks.xml</Actor>
    <FoundationActor>structures/fndn_6x6.xml</FoundationActor>
  </VisualActor>
</Entity>
