<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="template_structure_special_theater">
  <Identity>
    <Civ>athen</Civ>
    <SpecificName>Theatron</SpecificName>
    <Classes datatype="tokens">CivSpecific</Classes>
    <History>
        In Ancient Greece theaters were magnificent constructions, built so that the voices of the performers would reach every seat. The theater consisted of the stage, a place for the musicians, and the seats (the theatron).
        There were three genres performed: the Tragedy, Comedy, and Saytr Play. Tragedy plays are often thought to be an extension of ancient rites that were performed for Dionysus. Tragedies were solemn—well, tragedies detailed conflicts between men and the gods. Which, often as not, ended ill for the protagonists.
        The genre of Comedy, evolved over the years; first, there was Old Comedy (archaia) which consisted of crude attacks at political figures. Next was Middle Comedy, where the attacks focused less on individual people and more on society in general. Finally, during the reign of the Macedonians there was New Comedy, which focused more on everyday life.
        The last genre, the Saytr play, was a mixture of both and is called Saytr because it has a chorus of Saytrs who make crude jokes to lighten the mood.
        Greek plays are far different from even Shakespeare’s plays. At its heyday, there were at most three actors, who, with the aid of often grotesque masks, played all the parts. They were accompanied by a chorus of twelve singers.
        During the reign of Alexander the Great, Greek theater spread across the land and was later even enjoyed in ancient Rome.
        During the theater's heyday in Athens, plays were only performed during special celebrations and competitions. The playwrights wrote and directed the plays, and they were judged. The winner was rewarded with a prize which was traditionally a goat.
    </History>
  </Identity>
  <VisualActor>
    <Actor>structures/athenians/theater.xml</Actor>
    <FoundationActor>structures/fndn_theater.xml</FoundationActor>
  </VisualActor>
</Entity>
