<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="hoplite|template_unit_champion_infantry_spearman">
  <Identity>
    <Civ>mace</Civ>
    <Lang>greek</Lang>
    <GenericName>Macedonian Shield Bearer</GenericName>
    <SpecificName>Hypaspistḗs</SpecificName>
    <SelectionGroupName>units/mace/champion_infantry_spearman</SelectionGroupName>
    <Icon>units/mace/hypaspist.png</Icon>
    <Requirements>
      <Techs datatype="tokens">-phase_city unlock_champion_infantry</Techs>
    </Requirements>
    <History>
    Hypaspists (translating to shield-bearers) were a type of elite infantry under Philip II and his son Alexander the Great. Hellenistic successor states later adopted the concept. They were traditionally 3,000 men (three chiliarchies) strong. As an evolution of Macedonian foot companions, these soldiers were hand-picked or promoted for their merits and bravery. Because of their high skill and loyalty, they acted as the king's bodyguards and carried out special, delicate missions such as guarding the treasury or ambushing the enemy.
        Most importantly, however, hypaspists played a vital role in Macedonian battle tactics and success. The main body of the Macedonian infantry were phalangites standing in a phalanx. Because of their long sarissa pikes, the front line was nearly impossible for contemporary armies to break through. However, this arrangement left the sides (and the back) extremely vulnerable to incoming attacks.  
        And on the battlefield, hypaspists were tasked with guarding exactly this weak point (often at the right). It's still debated whether they were equipped as phalangites too or instead fought in a hoplite manner. Either way, they functioned as an entity seperate from the main formation and were therefore much more flexible.
    </History>
  </Identity>
  <Promotion>
    <Entity>units/mace/champion_infantry_spearman_02</Entity>
    <RequiredXp>2000</RequiredXp>
  </Promotion>
  <VisualActor>
    <Actor>units/macedonians/infantry_spearman_c_a.xml</Actor>
  </VisualActor>
</Entity>
