<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="civ/athen|template_unit_hero_infantry_swordsman">
  <Auras datatype="tokens">
    units/heroes/athen_hero_themistocles_1
    units/heroes/athen_hero_themistocles_2
  </Auras>
  <Identity>
    <GenericName>Themistocles</GenericName>
    <SpecificName>Themistoklēs</SpecificName>
    <Icon>units/athen/hero_themistocles.png</Icon>
    <History>
        Themistocles was an Athenian politician and general in the 5th century BC. He was known for his populist and democratic political beliefs, which were supported by the lower classes and generally opposed by Athens' higher society. 
        Themistocles was of the opinion that, quote: “He who commands the sea has command of everything.” He convinced the Athenians to expand the navy by building 200 triremes, making it, by far, the most powerful fleet in Greece.
        The ships would prove vital for the outcome of the second Persian invasion in 480 BC,  This war was, without a doubt, Themistocles' biggest achievement. While he was not the chief commander of the Greek-allied fleet, he was credited as being its chief strategist. After the Greeks were forced to retreat from their first battle with the Persians, Themistocles decided to evacuate Athens onto the newly constructed triremes. He led the fleet to the island of Salamis and waited for the Persians to attack. The two fleets clashed at Salamis' strait. There, the larger Persian ships had a hard time maneuvering in the strait's narrow confines. And, even though they were outnumbered, the smaller, more agile Greek ships won.
        Even though the Greeks had successfully defended their homeland, many cities, including Athens, had been completely destroyed. To avoid that happening again, Themistocles had a wall built around Athens and proposed the idea of building long walls to protect Athens and the passage to its port, Piraeus. These walls would not be built until 20 years later, but they turned out to be a core point of Athens' strategy in the wars to come.
        Although Themistocles was celebrated as a hero and the savior of Greece, as time went on, several accusations against him arose, and he lost his credence and the trust of the Athenian people. Eventually, he was ostracized and exiled from Athens around 471 BC, not even ten years after his huge victory. Ironically, Themistocles fled to Persia, where he was taken in by King Artaxerxes I, the son of the man he had fought against just a decade prior and lived there for the rest of his life.
    </History>
  </Identity>
  <VisualActor>
    <Actor>units/athenians/hero_infantry_swordsman_themistocles.xml</Actor>
  </VisualActor>
</Entity>
