<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="civ/athen|template_unit_support_female_citizen">
  <Identity>
    <SpecificName>Gýnē Athēnaía</SpecificName>
    <GenericName>Athenian Woman</GenericName>
    <Icon>units/hele/support_female_citizen.png</Icon>
    <History>
        Common belief is that women in ancient Athens and Greece in general were oppressed or even abused. In many cases, they were indeed inferior to their male counterparts. Legally, Athenian women were treated as children, they couldn’t buy property. And if they wanted to pursue something in Athens’ famed legal system, they needed their husband or another relative to represent them. Furthermore, there were no formal schools, for women any education they received would be at home.
        Athenian women married in their mid-teens, and rarely in the upper class did the woman have a choice in marriage. That was negotiations between her parents and the husband-to-be. Or, if the potential husband was young, his parents. However, according to the accounts we have, it was more likely to be the former, Greek men usually got married when they were well into their thirties. Like many arranged marriages, they were usually made for wealth and alliances, not for love. Among the lower classes, we have little historical evidence, but there have been found graves with tender inscriptions on them of husbands mourning their lost wives.
        The primary duty of an Athenian woman was to bear her husband an heir. Unfortunately, this also was the primary cause of death. Athenian women married in their mid-teens, and usually, were pregnant before their bodies had a chance to fully mature. Their youth and a combination of poor hygiene and little medical knowledge resulted a high death rate with new mothers.
        After childbearing, the Athenian women were expected to oversee the management of the household. That included, raising the children, cooking meals, spinning, weaving, cleaning, and shopping. Naturally, if the household was wealthy enough to have servants or slaves she’d be overseeing the tasks.
        Traditionally, the view is that ancient Greek women were forced to stay home. And with the responsibility of the household on them, it’s likely they did, to some extent at least. However, to what extent of their husbands forcing them, is doubtful, there were plenty of times when most of the men were called away at war, who would enforce such curfews then? While many of our sources fom literature discribe women staying home, some scholars belive it to be only idealized accounts. This theory is supported by poterry which depicts women participating in many activities abroad including symposiums. Besides, there were many religious festivals in ancient Athens that the women attended, some which they even excluded the men.
        Unfortunately, most historians write only about the upper class, so while there are few records of Greek women we are able to find information of the upper class from pottery, literature. The lower class were different. The orator Demothenes reported that after the Athenian defeat at the Peloponnesian War, that many women of the lower class had to work as weavers or grape pickers.
    </History>
  </Identity>
  <VisualActor>
    <Actor>units/athenians/female_citizen.xml</Actor>
  </VisualActor>
</Entity>
