<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="template_unit_hero_infantry_swordsman">
  <Auras datatype="tokens">
    units/heroes/han_hero_liu_bang_1
    units/heroes/han_hero_liu_bang_2
  </Auras>
  <Identity>
    <Civ>han</Civ>
    <SpecificName>Liú Bāng</SpecificName>
    <Icon>units/han/hero_liu_bang.png</Icon>
    <History>
        Liu Bang was born and grew up in the peasantry. When the Qin dynasty started to collapse with the many rebellions forming, Liu Bang was working as a local “police officer”. As once he was leading a group of prisoners, one escaped. Arriving late due to having to recapture the prisoner, or even worse, showing up with one prisoner missing, would likely both have him executed. So instead, he let all of them go and started revolting himself. Over the next few years, Liu Bang rose to become a successful general. However, it was Xiang Yu, the rebel leader, who ultimately defeated the Qin. Xiang Yu upon victory split China's land into eighteen kingdoms and instated nobles, or his generals, as rulers. Liu Bang received the land of Han.
        However, this didn't prove very stable. War broke out between the kingdoms again, and Liu Bang managed to take over several others. But despite his numerical superiority, he suffered heavy defeats against the state of Chu, led by Xiang Yu. Only when he combined the forces of many generals did Liu Bang beat Xiang Yu's forces in the Battle of Gaixia and encircle him. Although Xiang Yu was able to break through, he ultimately took his own life. Liu Bang had united China again, founded the Han dynasty in 202 BC, and appointed himself the first emperor, the Emperor Gaozu of Han.
        Liu Bang adopted many elements from the Qin dynasty. However, Liu Bang was also China's first ruler, originating from the peasantry. And this was clearly reflected in his decisions. He implemented policies lowering taxes on peasants to strengthen rural agriculture, thus restoring the war-impaired economy. He also reduced the severity of punishments from the Qin dynasty. This made Liu Bang very popular, especially among commoners. Inspired by a Confucianist teacher and philosopher, Liu Bang introduced Confucianism as the state ideology, in contrast to the legalistic approach present in the Qin dynasty.
        Although Liu Bang died of illness in 195 BC, the dynasty he had founded would go on to (with a short interruption) become the longest-lasting and one of the most prosperous' in Chinese history.
    </History>
  </Identity>
  <Promotion disable=""/>
  <VisualActor>
    <Actor>units/han/hero_infantry_liu_bang.xml</Actor>
  </VisualActor>
</Entity>
