<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="template_unit_hero_infantry_crossbowman">
  <Auras datatype="tokens">
    units/heroes/han_hero_wei_qing_1
    units/heroes/han_hero_wei_qing_2
  </Auras>
  <Attack>
    <Ranged>
      <Damage>
        <Crush>3</Crush>
      </Damage>
    </Ranged>
  </Attack>
  <Identity>
    <Civ>han</Civ>
    <SpecificName>Wèi Qīng</SpecificName>
    <Icon>units/han/hero_wei_qing.png</Icon>
    <History>
        Wei Qin's early childhood was unfortunately not a happy one. He was born illegitimately into a poor slave family. Because of his parentage, he was mistreated  by his family. So much so, in fact, that at the age of only around ten, he fled. Wei Qing eventually found his biological mother at the palace of Princess Pingyang and started working there. 
        Luck was on his side: when Emperor Wu himself visited the palace, he was impressed by Wei Qing's half-sister, Wei Zifu, and decided to take her to his imperial palace as a concubine. Wei Qing, as her brother, was taken there as well and got employment as a palace guard. However, for this honor he almost paid hid life: when Wei Zifu got pregnant with the emperor's first son, the empress got jealous. And for being her brother, Wei Qing was kidnapped and beaten almost to death. Fortunately, his friends rescued him and to punish the empress for ordering his beating, Emperor Wu promoted Wei Qing and elevated Wei Zifu to a consort.
        At the time, the Xiognu, a nomadic horse people inhabiting the regions north of the Han empire, were continuously raiding border regions. At this point, the Han had for decades been sending tribute payments, trying to make peace, which, didn't stop the Xiognu from pillaging. Emperor Wu decided to finally put an end to this problem. He tasked four generals with small cavalry armies to attack the Xiognu. Three of those were highly reputable generals. The fourth one, was Wei Qing.
        The results of the campaigns were surprising, The three generals either suffered heavy losses or failed to engage in battle with the enemy at all. Wei Qing, however, against everyone's expectations, was very successful and managed to plunder the Longcheng, a sacred location to the Xiognu people.
        Over the next ten years, Wei Qing conducted several more campaigns against the Xiognu. Even though the Xiognu, due to their nomadic lifestyle, were extremely difficult to fight, many of his expeditions succeeded. His army often killed tens of thousands of Xiognu soldiers, took a similar number of captives, and seized millions of cattle. And despite originating from such destitute backgrounds, Wei Qing was not even his family's only talented general. Huo Qubing, his nephew, accomplished similar feats. The two eventually managed to defeat the seemingly invincible enemy. The duo were celebrated as national heroes and were granted many honorary titles. Wei Qing even married Princess Pingyang, at whose palace he had served a few years prior. And his sister, Wei Zifu, was made empress by emperor Wu. Despite his great reputation and success, Wei Qing was said to remain a humble, calm, and prudent man. When he died, he was buried in great honor in the giant Maoling Mausoleum, along with Emperor Wu himself.
    </History>
  </Identity>
  <VisualActor>
    <Actor>units/han/hero_infantry_wei_qing.xml</Actor>
  </VisualActor>
</Entity>
