<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="template_unit_siege_stonethrower">
  <Identity>
    <Civ>han</Civ>
    <GenericName>Mangonel</GenericName>
    <SpecificName>Tóushí Chē</SpecificName>
    <Icon>units/han/siege_mangonel_packed.png</Icon>
    <History>
        Unlike ancient Western civilizations, the ancient Chinese did not use tension or torsion mechanisms for catapults. Instead, their catapults were man-powered: A long horizontal beam was attached to a hinge that was mounted on a framework. A sling was fastened to the end of the beam's back arm. Ropes hung down from the shorter front arm or from a short cross-beam. The team of men operating the catapult stood below the shorter arm. On command, they all pulled the ropes, causing the beam to rotate, the sling to open, and whatever projectile was placed in the sling (usually a stone) to be hurled forward. Such catapults are called mangonels, or traction trebuchets.
        When mangonels in the early Middle Ages also found their way from China to Europe, they proved to be superior to the traditional catapults there, powered by the tension of a bow or the torsion of sinew bundles. This was for several reasons: Firstly, they were simpler to construct and operate. Secondly, because of their mechanical simplicity they could be reloaded faster and fire at a higher rate. For the same reason, they were also way more reliable than the traditional torsion artillery. For example, in contrast to those, a mangonel's performance was not affected by damp weather conditions. Lastly, it could easily be scaled up or down for different needs by increasing or decreasing the number of men pulling the ropes. All in all, mangonels were more user-friendly, so to speak.
        In fact, the largest recorded mangonel in ancient China had 250 people pulling 125 ropes. The framework itself was still only a few meters large, which meant all 250 people were cramped up in  only a space of 33 square yards (40 square meters). This particular mangonel hurled stones of around 132 pounds (60 kilograms) more than 250 feet (75 meters). The largest ever recorded even required 600 pulling men. However, in the 12th and 13th centuries, mangonels were eventually displaced by the new counterweight trebuchets, which required fewer men to operate.
    </History>
  </Identity>
  <Pack>
    <Entity>units/han/siege_mangonel_unpacked</Entity>
    <State>packed</State>
  </Pack>
  <VisualActor>
    <Actor>units/han/siege_mangonel_pivot_packed.xml</Actor>
  </VisualActor>
</Entity>
