<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="encyclopedia/encyclopedia_trader|template_unit_support_trader">
  <Footprint replace="">
    <Square depth="8.0" width="4.0"/>
    <Height>3.0</Height>
  </Footprint>
  <Identity>
    <Civ>han</Civ>
    <SpecificName>Shāngrén</SpecificName>
    <Icon>units/han/support_trader.png</Icon>
    <History>
        In the Han dynasty's early days, the Xiognu, a hostile people inhabiting the lands north of the Han empire, were repeatedly plundering the border regions. The Xiognu were nomads and rode horses, which made them extremely difficult to fight against. For that reason, the Han saw no choice but to pay tribute to the Xiognu in order to make peace. However, despite the tribute payments, the Xiognu kept on pillaging. And thanks to the Xiognu and other natural barriers, the Han were almost completely cut off from the Western part of the world.
        Emperor Wu planned to finally put an end to the Xiognu, and so he sought allies to help. Wu thought that the Yuezhi, another nomadic people to the west of the Xiognu, would be willing to help. The Yuezhi had recently been defeated, and their king humiliated by the Xiognu. Emperor Wu sent an envoy, Zhang Qian, to try to form an alliance with the Yuezhi.
        The mission was very dangerous, as Zhang Qian had to travel through many hostile lands. Not long after his departure, he and his companions were captured by the Xiognu. While captive, Zang Qian took this opportunity to closely examine the Xiognu, their society, life, and fighting style. Finally, after ten years, a chance arose, and Zhang Qian fled to resume his mission.
        He eventually traversed the Xiognu regions and arrived at the Yuezhi. Those were, against his expectations, not keen on starting a war against the Xiognu. Still, many of the rulers he met were open to building relations with the Han. Zhang Qian spent another year there and studied the cultures of the peoples he encountered. This region, today the Stans in Central Asia, was previously completely unknown to the Han. And, since two hundred years prior, Alexander the Great had conquered this region and established colonies there, Zhang Qian even came into contact with ancient Greek culture, a society thousands of miles away from the Han dynasty. He even saw highly priced Chinese products that had found their way to this (for the Han) exotic place.
        With his newly acquired knowledge, Zhang Qian then returned to the Han dynasty. On his way, he was captured by the Xiognu again, but this time, after “only” one year, was able to escape again and successfully make his way home. He had been away for a total of 13 years.
        Even though he had failed his original mission of forming an alliance with the Yeuzhi, Zhang Qian returned with valuable information. From his narrations, the Han realized how highly foreigners valued Chinese products and recognized the need to finally defeat the Xiognu in order to have safe passage to these newly discovered lands. Zhang Qian's great knowledge about the Xiognu proved to be a big advantage for the Han in the war. When they had finally defeated the Xiognu, trade routes were set up along the path Zhang Qian took towards the west. This trade network would later even reach the Mediterranean and have a big impact on economies and cultures all over the world. It is today famously called the Silk Road.
    </History>
  </Identity>
  <VisualActor>
    <Actor>units/carthaginians/trader.xml</Actor>
  </VisualActor>
</Entity>
