<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="template_unit_ship_warship_heavy">
  <Cost>
    <Population>5</Population>
    <BuildTime>60</BuildTime>
    <Resources>
      <wood>800</wood>
      <metal>400</metal>
    </Resources>
  </Cost>
  <Footprint>
    <Square width="12.0" depth="48.0"/>
    <Height>8.0</Height>
  </Footprint>
  <GarrisonHolder>
    <Max>100</Max>
  </GarrisonHolder>
  <Health>
    <Max>4000</Max>
  </Health>
  <Identity>
    <Civ>ptol</Civ>
    <Classes datatype="tokens">Juggernaut</Classes>
    <GenericName>Juggernaut</GenericName>
    <SpecificName>Tessarakonterēs</SpecificName>
    <Icon>units/rome/ship_quinquereme.png</Icon>
    <History>
        Ships in Ancient Greece were named after the number of banks of oarsmen on each side. The earliest ships had just one row. Around the 7th century B.C., two- and three-rowed ships emerged, biremes ("twos") and triremes ("threes"). In the 4th century BC, larger "fours" (quadriremes) and "fives" (quinqueremes) became the dominant Mediterranean war vessels.
        Different Hellenistic monarchs tried to surpass each other by building larger and larger vessels. Especially the Ptolemies were known for building warships of enormous size. They constructed "sixes", "sevens", and "eights", eventually up to "sixteens" and "twenties", until Ptolemy IV finally built a "forty", the legendary Tesseraconter ("forty-rowed").
        Measuring a staggering 420 feet in length and 57 feet in width, the Tesseraconter remains the largest functional human-powered vessel of all time. It was powered by 4000 oarsmen and garrisoned by almost 3000 marines. 
        In terms of construction, it was an architectural masterpiece; it's unclear how a functional vessel of this size was built without any modern machinery. Though fully functional, it was more of a prestige vessel to show power rather than an effective warship. Its gigantic size made maneuvering and docking at harbors almost impossible. One theory suggests it might have been a catamaran featuring two "twenties" connected by a huge deck. Today, some people doubt this ship ever existed or claim the descriptions given by Plutarch and Athenaeus are exaggerations:
 
        "Philopator [Ptolemy IV] constructed his forty-bank ship with a length of 420 feet; its beam from gangway to gangway was 57 feet;
        its height to the gunwale was 72 feet. From the top of the stern-post to the water-line it measured 79.5 feet. It had four steering-oars, 45-foot-long,
        and the oars of the topmost rowers, which are the longest, measured 57 feet; these, since they carried lead on the handles and were very heavy inboard, were yet easy to handle in actual use because of their nice balance. It had a double-bow and a double-stern, and carried seven rams; one of these was the leader, others were of gradually diminishing size, some being mounted at the catheads. It carried 12 under-girders, each of them measuring 900  feet. It was extraordinarily well proportioned. Wonderful also was the adornment of the vessel besides;
        for it had figures at stern and bow not less than 18 feet high, and every available space was elaborately covered with encaustic painting; the entire surface where the oars projected, down to the keel, had a pattern of ivy-leaves and Bacchic wands. Rich also was the equipment in armament, and its satisfied all the requirements of the various parts of the ship. On a trial voyage it took more than 4000 men to man the oars, and 400 reserves; to man the deck there were 2850 marines." (Athenaeus, Deipnosophistae)
    </History>
  </Identity>
  <Loot>
    <xp>400</xp>
    <wood>160</wood>
    <metal>80</metal>
  </Loot>
  <TrainingRestrictions>
    <Category>Juggernaut</Category>
  </TrainingRestrictions>
  <VisualActor>
    <Actor>structures/romans/quinquereme.xml</Actor>
  </VisualActor>
</Entity>
