<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="template_unit_siege_boltshooter">
  <Attack>
    <Ranged>
      <Damage>
        <Pierce>160</Pierce>
      </Damage>
      <PrepareTime>3000</PrepareTime>
      <RepeatTime>4000</RepeatTime>
      <Splash>
        <Damage>
          <Pierce>50</Pierce>
        </Damage>
      </Splash>
    </Ranged>
  </Attack>
  <Identity>
    <Civ>ptol</Civ>
    <SpecificName>Polybolos</SpecificName>
    <Icon>units/hele/siege_oxybeles_packed.png</Icon>
    <History>
        The polybolos was a bolt-shooting device invented by Dionysius of Alexandria in the 3rd century B.C. Because it could fire automatically without manual reloading, it is often called "the first machine gun". It is an impressive piece of engineering and a remarkable achievement of the Ancient Greeks.
       Unlike the Greek oxybeles (Greek bolt shooter) and the gastraphetes (Greek crossbow), the polybolos was powered by a torsion mechanism. Torsion-based weapons can store and release energy more efficiently than tension-based weapons (like bows and crossbows).
        The polybolos had a chain drive system, with a wooden chain on each side of the polybolos. It ran over a five-sided prism on each end. Both chains were connected to a slider in the middle.
        To fire the polybolos, the wheels were first rotated forward, which made the slider go forward. On the back of the slider, there was a claw mechanism that, when moved forward enough, grabbed the bowstring. Above the slider, there was a cylinder with two grooves, one lengthwise and one helical. The end of a bent metal finger that was mounted on the slider and entered the helical groove. This way, as the slider was moved forward, the above cylinder rotated 180 degrees, which aligned the lengthwise groove with the opening to the arrow case and dropped an arrow into the groove.
        Then the wheels were turned backward, moving the slider back. The claw on the slider pulled along the string and rotated the attached wooden arms, which twisted sinew bundles to store the elastic energy. With the movement of the slider, the cylinder was rotated back 180 degrees, aligning the lengthwise groove (with the arrow inside) with the below opening and dropping the arrow onto the slider just in front of the string. As the slider was moved backwards even further, the claw automatically let go of the bowstring. This let the twisted sinew bundles untwist, releasing the stored energy and firing the arrow.
        By just rotating the wheels back and forth, arrows were continuously fired until the arrow case was empty. The polybolos was able to fire 10 to 12 arrows per minute up to several hundreds of yards away. This was multiple times faster than any other arrow or bolt-shooting device at the time. Compared to other devices like the oxybeles or the ballista, the polybolos sacrificed some of the shooting power for a higher fire speed. At close range, its arrows could still penetrate shields and armor.
        It's unknown how widely the polybolos was used and how effective it was in battle. Dionysius built it in Rhodes, probably for the Rhodians, who, at least during the Siege of Rhodes in 305–304 B.C., were allied with and supported by the Ptolemaic empire.
    </History>
  </Identity>
  <Pack>
    <Entity>units/ptol/siege_polybolos_unpacked</Entity>
    <State>packed</State>
  </Pack>
  <VisualActor>
    <Actor>units/ptolemies/siege_spear_packed.xml</Actor>
  </VisualActor>
</Entity>
