<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="template_structure_military_barracks">
  <Footprint>
    <Square depth="22.0" width="22.0"/>
    <Height>5.0</Height>
  </Footprint>
  <GarrisonHolder>
    <List datatype="tokens">Minister</List>
  </GarrisonHolder>
  <Identity>
    <Civ>han</Civ>
    <SpecificName>Jūn Yíng</SpecificName>
    <History>
        The largest part of the Han population consisted of peasants, and so raising armies was done through conscription. At the age of 23, later lowered to 20, Han men underwent two years of military service. One year they spent training, and the other in active service. After these two years, the citizens were released from active service. However, they were liable to still be called to arms until they turned 56. This allowed the Han dynasty to keep a small professional army during times of peace, while still being able to call upon a large force when they were at war. 
        However, over the course of time, local warlords and clans gained more and more power, weakening the central government's control over its citizens. This caused the conscription system to slowly collapse. These warlords raised their own private armies instead. And, at the beginning of the Eastern Han dynasty (first century AD), the strict standardized conscription system was more or less abolished. Commoners could now pay a certain tax to exempt themselves from service, which resulted in a drastic decline of conscripts in the army. Among other reasons, it would be this development of feudalism and privatization of the military that eventually caused the Han dynasty's downfall.
    </History>
  </Identity>
  <Obstruction>
    <Static depth="20.0" width="20.0"/>
  </Obstruction>
  <Researcher>
    <Technologies datatype="tokens">
      archer_attack_spread
      crossbow_training
    </Technologies>
  </Researcher>
  <Trainer>
    <Entities datatype="tokens">
      units/{civ}/infantry_crossbowman_b
    </Entities>
  </Trainer>
  <VisualActor>
    <Actor>structures/han/barracks.xml</Actor>
    <FoundationActor>structures/fndn_5x5.xml</FoundationActor>
  </VisualActor>
</Entity>
