<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="template_structure_military_barracks">
  <Footprint>
    <Square depth="22.0" width="22.0"/>
    <Height>5.0</Height>
  </Footprint>
  <GarrisonHolder>
    <List datatype="tokens">Minister</List>
  </GarrisonHolder>
  <Identity>
    <Civ>han</Civ>
    <SpecificName>Jūn Yíng</SpecificName>
    <History>
        The largest part of the Han population consisted of peasants. For this reason, raising armies was done through conscription. At the age of 23, later lowered to 20, Han men underwent two years of military service, one year of training, and one year of active duty stationed in the capital, provinces, or the northern frontier. After this, they were liable to be called to arms until the age of 56. Because of that, although the Han dynasty retained a small professional army, most soldiers were still militia units.
        However, over the course of time, local warlords and clans gained more and more power, weakening the central government's control over its citizens. This caused the conscription system to slowly collapse. These warlords raised their own private armies instead. And, at the beginning of the Eastern Han dynasty (first century AD), the strict standardized conscription system was more or less abolished. Commoners could now pay a certain tax to exempt themselves from service, which resulted in a drastic decline of conscripts in the army. Among other reasons, it would be this development of feudalism and privatization of the military that eventually caused the Han dynasty's downfall.
    </History>
  </Identity>
  <Obstruction>
    <Static depth="20.0" width="20.0"/>
  </Obstruction>
  <Researcher>
    <Technologies datatype="tokens">
      archer_attack_spread
      crossbow_training
    </Technologies>
  </Researcher>
  <Trainer>
    <Entities datatype="tokens">
      units/{civ}/infantry_crossbowman_b
    </Entities>
  </Trainer>
  <VisualActor>
    <Actor>structures/han/barracks.xml</Actor>
    <FoundationActor>structures/fndn_5x5.xml</FoundationActor>
  </VisualActor>
</Entity>
