<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="template_structure_military_barracks">
  <Footprint>
    <Square width="25.0" depth="25.0"/>
    <Height>12.0</Height>
  </Footprint>
  <Health>
    <SpawnEntityOnDeath>decay|rubble/rubble_stone_5x5</SpawnEntityOnDeath>
  </Health>
  <Identity>
    <Civ>spart</Civ>
    <SpecificName>Stratopedon</SpecificName>
    <History>
        The Agoge, the Spartan training and education system, was introduced somewhere around the 8th century BC by Lycurgus, the legendary lawgiver of Sparta. It was a state-sponsored program to teach children the values and skills necessary to fight for their homeland. Of course, this system was exclusive to the children of Spartan citizens, the highest class of Spartan society, the Spartiates. Although the Agoge was primarily focused on training boys into soldiers, the girls were also required to do different forms of exercise to stay fit, as it was believed that only men and women in peak physical conditions would produce strong and healthy offspring.
        Boys entered the Agoge around the age of seven, leaving their families to live in communal barracks with other boys, where they received a basic education in literature, music, and history. The group was supervised by an elderly Spartan veteran, who acted as their mentor and instructor, and by a group of young men aged 19 to 20, who enforced discipline and rules. Not only them, but all Spartan citizens were given the power to punish the boys by any means, be it the whip or the stick, for misbehavior or disobedience. Through this harsh regime, the boys learned to respect their elders, to be resourceful, to endure pain and hardship, and to obey orders without question. Spartans were renowned for their discipline and self-restraint, avoiding eye contact or conversation with strangers in public.
        As a preparation for times of war and crisis, the boys were forced to undergo harsh labor and physical training, with minimal clothing and no footwear whatsoever, no matter the weather or terrain (walking barefoot was believed to strengthen the feet). They learned to control their emotions, resist physical pain, and detach from any personal possession.
        Competition also played a very important role in the Agoge. The boys competed in various activities such as ball games, wrestling, races, and hunting meant to improve their agility, concentration, coordination, and teamwork skills. The games were often deliberately designed to create rivalries between groups or individuals that strived to outperform each other not only in training but also on the battlefield.
        As the boys grew older, they had to spend a certain period of time alone in the wilderness, known as "fox time". This was meant to test everything they had learned so far. In addition to hunting for food, it was encouraged to steal the food necessary to survive. However, when caught, the boys were punished severely and beaten up, not for the act of stealing itself but rather for being careless and caught. There is a tale of a Spartan boy who had stolen a fox and hidden it under his cloak. The fox started biting the boy, but instead of taking the embarrassment and shame of being caught stealing, he endured the pain and let the fox bite and gnaw him to death.
        Once old and strong enough, the boys would begin military training as hoplites.They learned how to fight with armor, shield, sword, and spear, and how to march and maneuver in the phalanx formation. A common activity was group dancing in full armor. It strengthened many muscles, enhanced agility and speed, and ingrained essential fighting movements into muscle memory. This armored dancing shows really well what the Agoge was all about: although it did include physical exercise, the Agoge was not focused on building purely muscle mass but on optimizing body strength and agility for hoplite combat.
        All Spartan citizens were expected to uphold the highest standards of bravery and fearlessness. Any act of cowardice, such as fleeing from a battle or failing the Agoge, was considered a disgraceful offense. Those who committed such acts were stripped of all their rights and forced to live in shame for the rest of their lives. This created such pressure that many Spartans preferred to die in battle rather than face the humiliation and dishonor of returning home as failures.
        All in all, the Agoge was a brutal and rigorous system that created the feared, merciless Spartan soldiers. Although the Agoge ultimately sealed Sparta's downfall, hindering adaptation and innovation in the Spartan society, it left a lasting mark on history as a unique system of an isolated society completely focusing all their means on training professional soldiers and developing a strong military that would, despite their small numbers, dominate ancient Greece for centuries.
    </History>
  </Identity>
  <Obstruction>
    <Static width="20.0" depth="20.0"/>
  </Obstruction>
  <VisualActor>
    <Actor>structures/spartans/barracks.xml</Actor>
    <FoundationActor>structures/fndn_7x7.xml</FoundationActor>
  </VisualActor>
</Entity>
